<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on the breadblog</title>
    <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on the breadblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:00:21 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ten grain porridge soaker</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/ten-grain-porridge-soaker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 22:00:21 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/ten-grain-porridge-soaker/</guid>
      <description>Using a soaker&amp;mdash;some raw or ground grain mixed in water, soaked for a bit, then added to the dough after the first mix&amp;mdash;you can put almost any grain into a sourdough loaf. For this loaf, I used some Bob&amp;rsquo;s Red Mill 10 grain hot cereal (good cereal, by the way):
 whole wheat, rye, triticale, millet, oats, brown rice, barley, corn, soy beans, oat bran and flaxseeds
 I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few loaves using this technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a big bloom and crackling crust</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/crackling-crust-big-bloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 23:47:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/crackling-crust-big-bloom/</guid>
      <description>You can tell a good crust by the way it crackles.
I mixed up this mostly-white loaf in the evening, and let it ferment overnight. By the morning, when I stretched and folded it a few times the dough felt pillowy but not too sticky. And during its long proof, it began to peek out from the top of the banneton.
All that airiness led to a great bloom, and the high-volume loaf had a wonderful open crumb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a long cold proof</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/a-long-cold-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 22:51:05 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/a-long-cold-proof/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, you just run out of time.
This was my second loaf with Community Grains flour. Like the first, a complet baked using more typical time and temperature, it came out great. In fact, its balance of wheat and sour flavors remains unique among my loaves. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t always seem that promising.
 Community Grains
  First, though the flour was great, I started late and ran into bed time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perfect pain integral with an open crumb</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/perfect-pain-integral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 10:26:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/perfect-pain-integral/</guid>
      <description>The holy grail of a whole grain hearth bread with an open crumb&amp;hellip;can be achieved&amp;mdash;even as a fleeting anomaly wholly dependent on the seasonal qualities of the grain used. &amp;mdash; Chad Robertson, Tartine Bread
 The bread below is the &amp;ldquo;holy grail&amp;rdquo;. It was delicious, so I hope it&amp;rsquo;s not too fleeting.
The crust is not very crunchy (compared to pain complet with at least 25% white flour) but the intense caramel wheat flavor makes up for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>community grains complet</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/first-community-grains-complet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 14:43:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/first-community-grains-complet/</guid>
      <description>In late 2013, I made my first loaf with hard red winter wheat flour from Community Grains. This stuff, which is milled at Certified Foods in Woodland, CA and marketed out of Oakland, is amazing.
I still remember the strength of the wheaty smell after mixing up the dough. It blew typical whole wheat flour out of the water. Some of this difference must owe to its freshness, but apparently some might owe to the milling process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>start it up</title>
      <link>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/start-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 13:47:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ashander.info/breadblog/post/start-it-up/</guid>
      <description>Bringing my loaf knowledge to the web.
I&amp;rsquo;ll kick this off with some loaves from the past, interspersed with current baking.
&amp;ndash; @jaimedash on twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>